# Sachin Shinde

Software Engineer sachin2smart@gmail.com

Montreal, QC (Canada) https://sachin2smart.github.io

https://linkedin.com/in/mastersachin

+1-438-995-4668

I am a software engineer at Cappemini and helps to a company to build the software products. Specifically, I have worked in Prime Brokerage, Capital Market, Equity Syndication and Reporting streams of Investment Banking. I have a good experience in Java technology. I am a good follower for the best practices to maintain a code quality, perform refactoring and applying software design principles for the various aspects of programming in daily activities. Data Structures, Algorithms and Problem-Solving Methodologies are my areas of interest.P

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## 1. Capgemini Solutions Canada Inc

Software Consultant 04/2021 - Present

- Enhancing the external user facing IPO financial application with BigDog, Kerberos, Siteminder authentication.
- Developed IPAD and DESKTOP application, designed various data compatible REST services

## 2. Capgemini India Pvt Ltd

Software Consultant

Pune, MH, India 03/2015 - 03/2021

Montreal, QC, Canada

- Developed microservices based Spring boot application for Equity Syndicate Platform and enriched with ADRs, logging, obo, access & data management.
- Worked to customize the product- TIBCO Data Virtualization by designing the java plugins. Designed & developed the custom java executables for the complex enterprise data collaborations including those for REST & SOAP service integration as well.
- Developed a web application for interactive web reporting.
- Created REST endpoints in java micro services SOA environment & designed Angular application to consume those REST services.
- Created a demo product for Box.com report delivery.

## 3. Amazon India

Hyderabad, TS, India 01/2014 - 06/2014

Intern

- Designed & developed a web UI for the Amazon's network connected Zebra printers in the Fulfillment Centers to perform remote operations.
- Maintained the reverse engineering mechanism to roll back the critical changes.
- Designed customer return labels in ZPL format for the EU & JP regions.

### 4. Mindstix Software Labs

Pune, MH, India 06/2013 - 11/2013

Intern

- Developed a web application for CMS system using the Grails frameworks.
- Designed the system in Groovy to manage contents for the Multi-tenant users. (Data placed on Amazon S3 & application runs on Amazon EC2 instance)
- Designed a customized filter to separate the roles of users.
- Designed a custom form validation JavaScript library.

#### TECH-STACK

Java, Spring, REST & SOAP, Cucumber, Gherkin, BDD, TDD, Angular, HTML, Mockito, jQuery, SonarQube, JUnit, SDLC, Agile, AWS, MongoDB, Groovy, Gradle, Ant, Jenkins, CI/CD, JIRA

#### **EDUCATION**

M.Tech in Computer Science, 2012-2014 Symbiosis Institute of Technology, Pune

**GitHub** : <a href="https://github.com/sachin2smart">https://github.com/sachin2smart</a> **LeetCode**: <a href="https://leetcode.com/sachin2smart">https://leetcode.com/sachin2smart</a>